# Amrendra Kumar

Software Engineer at Facebook

## Summary

I'm a passionate Android/Java Developer with 3+ years of hands-on experience in Android Application & Platform Fundamentals, Application Design & Architecture, Material Design, Object Oriented Concepts, Design Patterns, Data Structures & Algorithms.

I am always curious about learning new and upcoming technologies in tech world.

#### Highlights:

Google Developer Certification – Associate Android Developer

Udacity – Android Developer Nanodegree Graduate

Awarded Employee of the month for May 2015 at Samsung R&D Institute India.

Improved performance of PDF module of Document Service by 97%, in flagship Samsung Note 4.

#### Specialities:

Android Application Development, Java, C++, Git, Data Structures & Algorithms

# Experience

#### Software Engineer at Facebook

July 2017 - Present

#### **Software Developer at Epic**

October 2016 - June 2017 (9 months)

#### **Software Development Engineer at Amazon**

August 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Worked on Amazon BuyVIP Android app to provide the best UX experience to our customers.

#### Software Engineer at Samsung R&D Institute India

June 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Part of Samsung Enterprise & Services Innovation Team in Knox Group.

Worked on Document Service project, had ownership of pdf module Improved performance of pdf module by 97%.

Document Service was released in Samsung Note 4, and all next Samsung Note & Galaxy phones. Worked on OTP project, which was released in Samsung Galaxy S6.

# Education

## **Udacity**

Android Developer Nanodegree Graduate, Android Development, 2016

## Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology, Bhopal

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering, 2009 - 2013

**Activities and Societies:** Web Coordinator at VISION Technical events society at MANIT Bhopal, Member of College Web Team MANIT Bhopal

### Honors and Awards

Employee of the Month, Overall Best Talent, Top 10 in India, Top 10 in India

# **Amrendra Kumar**

Software Engineer at Facebook



Contact Amrendra on LinkedIn